So first thing first composition API anytime you create a reusable function with composition API
They we have landed on the turn composables not my favorite, but it's what we landed on so
Just know that
Going forward when you're looking at code bases and you see
over here
This little composables folder
That is what that is referring to basically composition API functions that you will be using inside of your code base
So the question is obviously what are composables exactly and so they're basically functionality that you want to be used throughout your components
Let's really what they are. Let's just give a quick demo of what that means
All right, I'm on my begin branch and then let me switch over to the exercise branch so that
That can give committed right
Okay, so
We have our composables folder and let's so let's start by taking a look at our task page
Right
And so you notice here on the task page we got there's a lot of stuff happening here
In fact, I'm noticing there is let's see there's a lot of weak stuff filter task. I mean, so look filter task
This looks like a very task specific thing and
As we can see here, it's actually being used in two different places is being used within the store
Which we'll talk more about later as well as within this page here. So this is something that's
Clearly right for some type of refactoring because
Basically, yep, there's no point in them having two different places. So let's go ahead and just refactor this
So we can use it. So first thing first
We're going to go ahead and we're going to create a new file inside of our composables directory
And so the standard for all composables is that you pre-fix it with the word use
And so in this case, we're just calling it used tasks.ts and again
It's a type fit file, but don't worry. We're really not using very much type fit, but all if any
And so then what I basically would do is I would go ahead and basically cut this out and throw this over here
And then that's gone
And then I'd go ahead and take a look at the task store
And where is that filter?
Here you go. Here's the folder. So this is the actual method as we can see here. There is a lot going on here
So what we're going to do is I'm going to do the controversial thing and we'll talk about this more when do stores later
I am actually going to take this out of the store and put it in a composable
So here we're going to take the filter task method and
So this actually I'm just going to replace this one right here
Okay, and then so we have the filters and
Then the data and then that is a function
That will yep, and then what we need to do then is be able to access the task list
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to actually say task list is when to be a task like this that we're going to pass in
And so it'll be basically an argument that we're passing into our composable
And then I think everything is mostly good from there
All we need to do now is import the type to to say it's a type task and that it uses task filters
And then we're going to export this as such and there you go now. It's formatting correctly
Okay, so now what we have here is a reusable JavaScript function
Right that's what we have and so what we can do now is inside of our task store
I actually can leave it out because the only the only place is actually being called was here
Inside of the filter method, but I no longer need this anymore
Because what I can do then is basically say okay, I'm going to import
That that was a filter tasks from my composable use task
That's really all the composable is it's allowing us to basically
Module or eyes parts of our script set up block into different files that we can then import
Really that's what it is that is simplest
And I want to emphasize that because I remember when I first was introduced to this sort of concept and if you're new to jobs
You can feel kind of intimidating to move stuff to files and then especially you don't know how imports work
We'll talk a little bit more about naming strategy in a sec
But that's this is really
It's core what it is and so the reason composable has become very popular is because rather than grouping things via how they work in view
So if we have like state
Actions get or so we would organize them via data
Compute it and all those things you can now organize them via
functionality via features and so as this right rather than calling like some sort of filter
We know that this is associated with our task feature so we can drag that in and so let's drag one more thing here
Let's say format status this is very specific actually to
Tests but it actually looks like it's generic but from what I remember this one is pretty specific so we can take that out
And let's see I like to do things alphabetical as if I can so there you go this is filter
So we're gonna have the format status but
um
Label I like to be very specific with these so that you can tell kind of what is going on here
So for my task status label, I think we'd be good enough
And then all we got to do to expose anything is the export keyword that is the main thing here
Once you have that we can go ahead and now we can at the top we can import format task label
But it was format status before so we need to make sure we update that
format has status label